MAHER ALI

Senior HR Professional | HR Business Partner | HR Strategist |

Location: Karachi, Pakistan Contact Number: +92-345-3042708

Email address: maher.aly@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maherali/

A brief about Maher Ali:

I have an amazing career in HR domain, As a person, I am a result-oriented and pro-active Human Resource professional with a zeal to climb the ladder, served diverse industries, capable of leading strategic & tactical HR Business practices across industry strokes.

With over 11+ years of experience in Human Resource, I have served various organizations, have worked on critical dimensions of HR, such as worked on HR Business Partnering, HR policy development & implementation, HR structuring, ERP Implementation, Compensation & Benefits, Performance management, Learning & Development, govt. compliance etc.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

A. Moosajee Sons Head of Human Resources Karachi March, 2021 - Date

A. Moosajee Sons is a well-established and well-known retail brand, started in 1854, it is dealing in Men's Suiting, Readymade cloths and Accessories.

As Head of HR, I am responsible to manage all domains of HR that include HR Budgeting & planning, Recruitment & Selections, Trainings, Performance management, Compensation & benefits etc. As a senior member, I am also part of the management committee for strategic business planning.

International Hospitality Investment Group Head of Human Resources Karachi October, 2019 - March, 2021

International Hospitality Investment Group (IHIG) is working in Hospitality, Tourism & Real Estate sector, providing Vacation Ownership & Fractional Ownership.

As Head of HR, I am responsible in managing end to end HR functions including HR Budgeting, managing HR planning cycle, preparing and implementing various HR policies and operational SOPs, managing Recruitment & Selection process, overseeing Compensation & Benefits, Training & Development, Performance Management, Employee Engagement & dealing with government compliance related matters. Also providing Consultation to the Board on HR and strategic related matters.

I am also managing HR portfolio for IHIG, PAK managed resorts & hotels at various locations in Pakistan. As Head of HR, I was reporting to the CEO and BODs.

Freelance HR Consultant

Karachi

July, 2018 - July, 2019

I have been working as Freelance HR Consultant on various Recruitment, HR policies, HR structuring, Consultancy projects with different clients in Pakistan.

The City School Regional Manager Human Resource Karachi January. 2018 - June, 2018

As Regional HR Manager, my responsibilities included managing City School's Southern Region's HR functions. I have managed HR Budgeting, Recruitment & Selection of staff, looking after Orientation modules, OD & Employee Engagement related activities, ensuring HR Audit & Compliance, managing Regional Compensation & Benefits, implementing HR policies & SOPs implementation & Govt. compliance related matters.

As Regional HR Manager, functionally I was reporting to Director HR at the Head office in Lahore and administratively I was reporting to Assistant Regional Director in Karachi

Al-Karam Group of Industries (AK Marketing & Al-Karam Textiles) Manager Human Resource

Karachi January, 2014 - December, 2017

At Al-Karam Group, I was part of Retail arm and was managing end to end HR work for the fashion brands of Alkaram Studio, Alkaram Fabrics, Babyshop, Splash, Lifestyle, Shoemart & MANGO at more than 45 locations across Pakistan & also one store in Dubai.

As Manager HR, I was managing complete HR domain from HR planning, HR budgeting, Recruitment & Selection (stores, Head office & Warehouses), Performance Management, OD, HR Policies and procedures etc., Succession planning, Govt. compliance (EOBI, SESSI, PESSI). I was also part of steering committee for MS Dynamics AX implementation.

I was also part of steering committee for MS Dynamics AX implementation.

Ghazi Brothers Manager Human Resource

Karachi March, 2011 - January, 2014

Ghazi Brothers deals with Animal Health and Poultry products, having its operations in 20 major cities of Pakistan, making it one of the leading companies providing Animal health care products in the country.

Ghazi Brothers didn't had any formal HR department. Upon my joining, I initiated a structured HR department. As HR Manager, I have initiated things from scratch. I have handling HR policies, HR planning, Recruitment & Selections for various positions, Performance management (for Sales & back end staff), Compensation and Benefits, Learning & Development, HRIS

I was also part of steering committee for MS Dynamic AX implementation at Ghazi Brothers.

BDO Pakistan Human Resource Officer

Karachi April, 2009 - March, 2011

BDO Ebrahim & Co. is a member firm of BDO International, 5th largest accountancy network in the world, a worldwide professional services network of Public Accountancy firms, serving National and International clients. BDO has Member Firms in 151 countries, employs around 60,000 staff in 1,328 offices worldwide.

As HR Officer, I have managed Recruitment & Selection, HR policies, payroll cycle, training & development, HR operational work, managing data and a focal person for ICAP, ACCA, ICAEW at BDO Pakistan's Karachi & Lahore offices.

EDUCATION:

Master's in Business Administration Hamdard University	2009
Post Graduate Diploma Hamdard University	2008
Bachelor's in Commerce University of Karachi	2005

SKILLS:

- HR Business Partnering

Strong Negotiation Skills

- Conflict Management & Problem Solving

- Experienced on Microsoft Dynamics AX & Oracle

- Sensible, Honest Ethics
- People Management

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

International Hospitality Investment Group:

I have started a chit-chat session with employees by the name of "Coffee Sessions with HR".

It gave an amazing response from employees, they shared their views and their career & life journey. It served as an amazing point for employee engagement

Al-Karam Group:

I alongwith my IT team developed an in-house ERP for HR which then became primary HR ERP for attendance, salaries, staff transfers, centralized database.

Ghazi Brothers:

I was part of steering committee and was an active member of the team for ERP Microsoft Dynamics AX

HOBBIES:

- Travelling
- Networking with people from various industries